Harpreet Singh

Thornville Avenue, Dublin 5

☐ (+353) 83 848 8767 | Singhh@tcd.ie | ★ www.harpreet.me | ☐ etSingh | ☐ etSingh

Summary _

Recently graduated from Trinity College Dublin with an M.Sc. in Computer Science with Distinction. Demonstrated capability of working in a team, in order to deliver high quality software. I want to employ my skill set in a Software Engineering role to further my knowledge and expertise.

Education ____

Trinity College Dublin

Dublin, Ireland

M.Sc. Computer Science, Networks and Distributed Systems

Sep. 2015 - Sep. 2016

• Grade: Distinction

University of Delhi

B.Sc. Physical Sciences

New Delhi, India

July 2012 - June 2015

• Grade: I, First class Honours (75%)

Research _____

Postgraduate Research Dissertation, Trinity College Dublin

Dublin, Ireland

Proactive Configuration of Data Centre Networks

Apr. 2016 - Sep. 2016

- The Research was aimed at optimizing data centre networks for Big Data processing applications, specifically Hadoop, in Proactive manner using Software-Defined Networking.
- Proactive flow scheduling was evaluated on the basis of the network throughput achieved and job completion times of **Hadoop** jobs running in a **16 host cluster** emulation.
- Development was done using **Python**, while **Git** was used for source control.

Experience _____

Software Engineering Group Project, Trinity College Dublin

Dublin, Ireland

www.zooop.xyz

Dec. 2015 - Mar. 2016

- Zooop was a finalist at the **Citibank upStart Programme 2016**. It is a platform that let's food vendors push real time advertisements to an Android application from a Web portal.
- Developed a Web Application and an Android Application using Test-Driven Development and Agile Methodologies in a group of four developers.
- Web application was developed using **AngularJS**, **MongoDB** and **Node.JS**, while the mobile application was developed for **Android** using **Java**.

Networked Applications Project, Trinity College Dublin

Dublin, Ireland

www.organisr.xyz

Jan. 2016 - Mar. 2016

- Organisr is a platform that enables instructors of amateur sports clubs to organize training sessions.
- Developed a Web Application using Facebook Graph API, MongoDB, Node.JS and AngularJS in a group of 5 developers, which was deployed on Heroku.

Individual Programming Project, Trinity College Dublin

Dublin, Ireland

https://github.com/etSingh/P2PChatServer

Oct. 2015 - Dec. 2015

- Using **UDP Sockets**, developed a Peer-to-Peer Chat Server based on the *Pastry routing protocol*.
- Acquired extensive experience of developing applications with Ruby and using Git for version control.

Undergraduate Final Project, University of Delhi

New Delhi, India

Obstruction Avoiding Arduino Robot

Jan. 2015 - Apr. 2015

- Designed an autonomous robot using the **Arduino Microcontroller** which avoided obstructions in its path by using an Ultra-Sonic sensor.
- Gained experience of Embedded programming using **C**.

Skills

Programming Python, Ruby, Java, Node.JS, C/C++, LaTeX

Web Express with Node.JS, AngularJS, MongoDB, HTML5, CSS

Tools Git, Vim, Linux, Mininet **Languages** English, Hindi, Punjabi

Extracurricular Activities _____

Dublin University Rifle Club

Dublin, Ireland

Sept. 2015 - PRESENT

• Member of the squad for 0.22 small bore rifle.

'Ankur' Theatre Society, University of Delhi

New Delhi, India

Assistant Director of a Street Play

July 2012 - March 2014

• Responsible for managing and creatively driving a cast and crew of 20 people of a street play production of which was critically appreciated in the Delhi University Theatre Circuit and won numerous competitions.

Awards

INTERNATIONAL

Active Member

3rd Position, "Quanta, the annual International Competition in Science"-Designed a model motor boat that was made to race among-st 2010 other competitors in a swimming pool, with schools from **16 different** countries participating.

Lucknow, India

DOMESTIC

Michelle's Cup, Awarded for being the best all-rounder student of St. 2011 Jude's School.

Dehradun, India

References ____

Prof. Stefan Weber

032 Lloyd Institute Trinity College Dublin Stefan.Weber@scss.tcd.ie